GARRARD KITCHEN, B.Sc (Hons)

+44 (0)1704 233 521 +44 (0)7795 575 000 garrardkitchen@gmail.com www.garrardkitchen.com skype: garrard.kitchen

1 Beresford Drive Churchtown Southport PR9 7JY

Interests include:

- Serverless technology
- Machine Learning
- Security
- Research
- Project Management
- Product Owner

Ideal locations:

- Southport
- Liverpool
- Manchester
- Preston

Full driving license

Profile

I am a technical project leader, experienced in communicating at all levels, with commercial awareness, I am accustomed to identifying improvement opportunities outside of scope. I have a proven track record of systems integrations, acting as a remote worker manager of a European team, project managing across multiple time zones and cultures. I have a strong technical background in both server & client side development as well as serverless technologies (infrastructure, services & frameworks) and solutions delivery driven by DevOps, UX.

Experience

CTO, Qualtrak Solutions; Remote worker — Sep 2008—Present
I manage a team of remote workers around Europe to develop single server, HA & cloud based solutions using a range of technologies.
I lead technical projects, architecting product systems and feature solutions and coordinating integrations with partner/SI teams around the globe.
The role is varied; ranging from technical presentations to CxO to root cause analysis. I categorise myself as a CTO/developer. Reporting directly to the CEO.

Contractor, Qualtrak Solutions; Remote worker — Jan 2007—Sep 2008
I was employed originally to develop an API for a company's client/server product. This involved employing Unit testing techniques such as TDD and documentation software and then to ship to integration partners.
I was also awarded the project to design and develop an e-learning and coaching web platform, hosted on self-managed Rackspace servers.
The work gave me my first experience of AWS services.
I worked with partners & system integrators around the world. I was asked to work full-time.

Contractor, Co-Op; Bromsgrove — 2005—Jan 2006
I was commissioned to support and enhance solutions using ASP, ASP.NET, c#, javascript, HTML and CSS. This role also included supporting Cadbury's with the Holos product (EIS). I was asked to work full-time.

Client-side web developer Team Lead, AIM Technology — Apr 2003—2004 I headed up the client-side development effort of a Scorecard web-application. This was eventually bought by Aspect.

Data Architect, AIM Technology - Nov 2002-Aug 2003

My primary role was to consolidate data from disparate systems into a Scorecard application. My responsibilities included providing an OLAP solution, BI, data analytics, pre-sales support, product installation, support and diagnostics. I worked both onsite and offsite. Other duties included enhancing the corporate website.

Education

John Moores University, Liverpool — Business Information Systems Degree (Hons), 1994

North East Wales Institute, Connah's Quay - National Diploma in Computer Science, 1990

Certification

AWS Solutions Architect - Associate Certification, 2018-2021 AWS Developer - Associate Certification, 2017-2020 1st Dan, Black belt, 2010

Skills

Technical project leadership, remote team management, technical presentations and documentation, experienced in communication at all levels, meeting facilitator, educator, coach, agile development, root cause analysis and problem solving, AWS certified, full-stack developer, serverless development, CI/CD, system integration, RDBMS, NoSQL, ElasticSearch, Big Data, containers (ECS Fargate, Linux, Windows), CloudFormation (configuration as code), git, C#, F#, javascript, .NET Core, <u>ASP.NET</u> Core Razor Pages, Python, Node.js, Go, ETL, Microsoft, Linux, Authentication, Azure, UX

References

Costas Johnson - CEO Qualtrak Solutions, +44 (0)777 5520 459, costas.johnson@qualtrak.com

Hobbies

Cycling, reading, research, cooking, walking, drone flying, golf and Ju-Jitsu